What is the Production Environment?
DEFINE VCS?, Git, GitHub – Introduction & Installation
Hosting Service of Choice – pythonanywhere.com/Heroku.com
Setting up the Production Environment
Configuring Settings for a Production Environment
Uploading Project on Server
Creating a Superuser
Making a Django Web Application
Settings for Security
Settings for Static Files and Allowed Hosts
Search the URL in the Browser

What is the Production Environment?
A server computer is nothing but a computer. The special thing about a server computer is that it’s connected to internet 24×7. It has a server program, backend and everything your website needs. Therefore, it is often called a production environment.

A production environment is capable of running and serving your website to users. The production environment can include:
    Computer Hardware
    Operating System like windows, ubuntu, etc.
    Support for a programming language like Python Interpreter
    Web Server like Apache, Nginx, etc.
    Application server
    Databases on which our website is built
    Some extra tools like a load balancer, proxy server, etc.

Hosting platforms provide infrastructure as a service (IAAS) to developers. So developers need not buy hardware. They can skip to the part of the software configuration. This is an application of cloud computing and is called IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service). These hosting companies can also provide a PaaS (Platform as a Service). You can actually create a computer with chosen hardware specifications. You can select everything from OS to software installed. Cloud technology has lots of applications. We are going to use one of them.

Hosting platforms are better for every developer who is a beginner. Since we as developers get a chance to showcase our work for free. We will be using pythonanywhere.com for this purpose. There are several hosting platforms available like AWS, Heroku, Digital Ocean, etc.

https://djangofriendly.com

DEFINE VCS?
Git – Introduction & Installation
A Version Control System allows you to track the history of a collection of files. It supports creating different versions of this collection. These versions are stored in a specific place, typically called a repository.

Version Control System
It is a software that helps software developers to work together and maintain a complete history of their work.

Functions of a VCS
    Allows developers to work simultaneously.
    Does not allow overwriting each other’s changes.
    Maintains a history of every version.

Types of VCS
    Centralized version control system (CVCS).
    Distributed/Decentralized version control system (DVCS).

Localized and centralized version control systems
A localized version control system keeps local copies of the files. This approach can be as simple as creating a manual copy of the relevant files.

A centralized version control system provides a server software component which stores and manages the different versions of the files. A developer can copy (checkout) a certain version from the central sever onto their individual computer.

Centralized PIC:

Distributed version control systems
In a distributed version control system each user has a complete local copy of a repository on his individual computer. The user can copy an existing repository. This copying process is typically called cloning and the resulting repository can be referred to as a clone.

Distributed PIC:

What is Git?
Git is currently the most popular implementation of a distributed version control system. Git originates from the Linux kernel development and was founded in 2005 by Linus Torvalds. 

Advantages of Git
1 Free and open source
2 Fast and small
3 Implicit backup
4 Security
5 No need of powerful hardware
6 Easier branching

DVCS Terminologies
Local Repository 	
Working Directory and Staging Area or Index
Blobs	Trees	Commits
Branches	Tags	Clone
Pull	Push	HEAD
Revision	URL

Git - Environment Setup 
https://gitforwindows.org/

Git Lfie Cycle..!!

After successfull installation go to command prompt.
list of all git commands displayed
$git

If any Error configure the following path @ Environment Variables..!!
C:\Program Files\Git\bin

displays all sub commands
$git help -a

displays help related to command
$git help command

Setting username
$ git config --global user.name "subbarajuk"

Setting email id
$ git config --global user.email "ksrajudatascientist@gmail.com"

Install Git on Linux Debian / Ubuntu (apt-get)
$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install git
$ git --version
$ git config --global user.name "subbarajuk"
$ git config --global user.email "ksrajudatascientist@gmail.com"

Listing Git settings
$ git config --list

GitHub
GitHub Inc. is a web-based hosting service for version control using Git. It is mostly used for computer code. It offers all of the distributed version control and source code management functionality of Git.

GitHub essentials are:
    Repositories
    Branches
    Commits
    Pull Requests
    Git (the version control software GitHub is built on)

Repository
A GitHub repository can be used to store a development project.
It can contain folders and any type of files (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Documents, Data, Images).
A GitHub repository should also include a licence file and a README file about the project.
A GitHub repository can also be used to store ideas, or any resources that you want to share.

Branch
A GitHub branch is used to work with different versions of a repository at the same time.
By default a repository has a master branch (a production branch).
Any other branch is a copy of the master branch (as it was at a point in time).

Commits
At GitHub, changes are called commits.
Each commit (change) has a description explaining why a change was made.

Pull Requests
Pull Requests are the heart of GitHub collaboration.
With a pull request you are proposing that your changes should be merged (pulled in) with the master.
Pull requests show content differences, changes, additions, and subtractions in colors (green and red).

Difference between Git and GitHub:
Git				
1 Installed Locally			
2 Released in 2005			
3 Maintained by Linux Foundation 	
4 Focused on Version Control		
5 A command line tool			
6 Provides a desktop interface named Git GUI
7 No user management features
8 Open Source

GitHub
1 Hosted in the Cloud
2 Launched in 2008
3 Purchased in 2018 by Microsoft
4 Focused on Centralized source code hosting & Code Sharing 
5 Administered through the web
6 Desktop Interface named GitHub Desktop
7 Builtin User Management
8 Includes a free tier and Pay for use tiers

Bitbucket
Bitbucket is a web-based version control repository hosting service owned by Atlassian.
OR
Bitbucket is a system for hosting version control repositories. It is a competitor to GitHub.

Difference between Github and Bitbucket
Github and Bitbucket are two of the biggest web-based hosting services for source code and advancement ventures.

Github
1) Github provides you inline editing and network graphs 
2) Github's monthly price is cheap, 
3) Github doesn't provide any free private repositories 
4) UI tool 

Bitbucket
1 Bitbucket doesn't provide inline editing and network graphs
2 Bitbucket is cheaper than Github.
3 Bitbucket provides you unlimited free private repositories.
4) UI tool

What is Virtual Environment?
A virtual environment (also called a venv) is a Python environment such that the Python interpreter, libraries and scripts installed into it are isolated from those installed in other virtual environments.

Why the Need for Virtual Environments?
Python, like most other modern programming languages, has its own unique way of downloading, storing, and resolving packages (or modules). 

Creating Virtual Environments
Open your command prompt(type cmd in your run terminal). Now go to the directory path(location), where you want to install the virtual environment.
$pip install virtualenv

How to Update Virtual Environment:
$pip install -U virtualenv

Creating Environment variable
Syntax:
$virtualenv <AnyName>
Example:
$virtualenv pypro

Go to C:\Users\admin
Check the pypro Environment variable, It contains all Python required files.

C:\Users\admin>cd pypro
C:\Users\admin\pypro>cd scripts

C:\Users\admin\pypro>tree /f

Activating Virtual Environment:
C:\Users\admin\pypro\scripts>activate

De-activating Virtual Environment:
C:\Users\admin\pypro\scripts>deactivate


What is Web Hosting ?
A web hosting service is a type of Internet hosting service that allows individuals and organizations to make their own website accessible via the World Wide Web.

What is Domain Name?
Domain names are used in various networking contexts and application-specific naming and addressing purposes. Domain names are used to identify one or more IP addresses. Domain names consist of two parts. 

1. Primary Level Domain (PLD)
2. Top Level Domain (TLD)

1. Primary Level Domain
It is end user requirement based business needs.

Example:
nareshit, google, facebook, amazon, twitter .................!!

2. Top Level Domain:
The following are the common TLDs:
in - India,  gov - Government agencies, edu - Educational institutions
org - Organizations, mil - Military, com - commercial business

How to Register a Domain Name:
Heroku is a container-based cloud Platform as a Service (PaaS). Developers use Heroku to deploy, manage, and scale modern apps. Heroku was acquired by Salesforce.com in 2010. Heroku Postgres is a managed SQL database service provided directly by Heroku.