What is the Production Environment?
A server computer is nothing but a computer. The special thing about a server computer is that it’s connected to internet 24×7. It has a server program, backend and everything your website needs. Therefore, it is often called a production environment.

A production environment is capable of running and serving your website to users. The production environment can include:
    Computer Hardware
    Operating System like windows, ubuntu, etc.
    Support for a programming language like Python Interpreter
    Web Server like Apache, Nginx, etc.
    Application server
    Databases on which our website is built
    Some extra tools like a load balancer, proxy server, etc.

Hosting platforms provide infrastructure as a service (IAAS) to developers. So developers need not buy hardware. They can skip to the part of the software configuration. This is an application of cloud computing and is called IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service). These hosting companies can also provide a PaaS (Platform as a Service). You can actually create a computer with chosen hardware specifications. You can select everything from OS to software installed. Cloud technology has lots of applications. We are going to use one of them.

Hosting platforms are better for every developer who is a beginner. Since we as developers get a chance to showcase our work for free. We will be using pythonanywhere.com for this purpose. There are several hosting platforms available like AWS, Heroku, Digital Ocean, etc.

https://djangofriendly.com

DEFINE VCS?
Git – Introduction & Installation
A Version Control System allows you to track the history of a collection of files. It supports creating different versions of this collection. These versions are stored in a specific place, typically called a repository.

Version Control System
It is a software that helps software developers to work together and maintain a complete history of their work.

Functions of a VCS
    Allows developers to work simultaneously.
    Does not allow overwriting each other’s changes.
    Maintains a history of every version.

Types of VCS
    Centralized version control system (CVCS).
    Distributed/Decentralized version control system (DVCS).

Localized and centralized version control systems
A localized version control system keeps local copies of the files. This approach can be as simple as creating a manual copy of the relevant files.

A centralized version control system provides a server software component which stores and manages the different versions of the files. A developer can copy (checkout) a certain version from the central sever onto their individual computer.

Centralized PIC:

Distributed version control systems
In a distributed version control system each user has a complete local copy of a repository on his individual computer. The user can copy an existing repository. This copying process is typically called cloning and the resulting repository can be referred to as a clone.

Distributed PIC:

What is Git?
Git is currently the most popular implementation of a distributed version control system. Git originates from the Linux kernel development and was founded in 2005 by Linus Torvalds. 

Advantages of Git
1 Free and open source
2 Fast and small
3 Implicit backup
4 Security
5 No need of powerful hardware
6 Easier branching

DVCS Terminologies
Local Repository 	
Working Directory and Staging Area or Index
Blobs	Trees	Commits
Branches	Tags	Clone
Pull	Push	HEAD
Revision	URL

Git - Environment Setup 
https://gitforwindows.org/

Git Lfie Cycle..!!

