STEP1:delete.html
<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">
<head>
    <meta charset="UTF-8">
    <title>Data Delete..!!</title>
         </head>
<body>
<div>
    Data Deleted Successfully......
    click here to see <a href="{% url 'home' %}"><h3>Companies List</h3></a>
</div>
</body>
</html>

STEP2:home.html
<!DOCTYPE html>
{% load static %}
<html>
    <head>
        <title>HomePage_CRUD_OPERATIONS</title>
    </head>
    <body>
        <a href="{% url 'home' %}"> Companies List </a>
            <a href="/create/">AddNewPic</a><br>
             {% for obj in orglist %}
                <a href="{{ obj.get_absolute_url }}"> {{ obj.id }}.{{ obj.cname }}
                {% if obj.cpic %} <img src='{{obj.cpic.url}}'/>
                {% endif %} </a>
        <a href="{% url 'update' id=obj.id  %} ">Update</a>|
        <a href="{% url 'delete' id=obj.id  %} ">Delete</a>
            {% endfor %}
    </body>
</html>

STEP3:views.py
def org_delete(request,id=None):
	instance =get_object_or_404(Company,id=id)
	instance.delete()
	return render(request,"MyApp/delete.html")

STEP4:urls.py
path('delete/<int:id>',views.org_delete,name='delete'),

STEP5:Send the request to WebServer..!! 
http://127.0.0.1:8000/delete/1 
OR
http://127.0.0.1:8000 ==> Click on DELETE

WebServices
Web service is a way of  communication (OR) a technology. 
Web Services allows us to build  interoperable distributed applications.

Interoperability Means?
Interoperability means language independent and platform independent

What is the difference between a web application and web service?
A Web Application is a server side  application which provide the  services directly to enduser(customer).
A webservice is also server side application which provides  it's services to another  application but not to end users directly.

WebServices :-
Web Services also allows a program to expose objects over the Network, WebServices are given by the open community  organization,called WS-I ,stands for WebService Interoperability Org

Types of Web Services:
There are 2 types of web services
1)SOAP Based WebServices/ Big Web Services
2)RESTful WebServices

1) SOAP Based Web Services:
SOAP: Simple Object Access Protocol. It is an XML based protocol for accessing web services. SOAP Based Web Service Components are:  Web Service Description Language  & Universal Description, Discovery, and Integration
 
Features of Soap Web Services
1 Secured		2 Language and Platform independent

Limitations of Soap Web Services
1 Slow	2 WSDL dependent:

2) RESTful Web Services:
REST stands for REpresentational State Transfer. It means that each unique URL is a represention of some object. We can get contents of this object by using HTTP GET, we can modify by using PUT/PATCH and we can delete by using DELETE.

Features of RESTful Web Services
1. Faster      2. Architectural Style

Limitations:
1. It is less secured.  2 Transfer Over http only

Note: 
Because of ligth weight, high performance, less bandwidth requirements, easy development, human understandable message format, this type of web services are most commonly used type of web services currently.

Differences between SOAP and REST
SOAP
1) XML Based Message Protocol.
2) Uses WSDL for communication between consumer and provider.
3) Invokes services by using RPC(Remote Procedure Call) Method calls.
4) Does not return human readable result.
5) These are heavy weight.
6) These require more bandwidth.
7) Can provide support for multiple protocols like HTTP,SMTP,FTP etc.
8) Performance is Low.
9) More Secured.

REST
1) An Architecture Syle but not protocol.
2) Uses xml/json to send and receive data.
3) Invokes services by simply URL Path.
4) Returns readable results like plain xml or JSON.
5) These are light weight.
6) These require less bandwidth.
7) Can provide support only for protocols that provide URI, mostly HTTP.
8) Perforamnce is High.
9) Less Secured.